Finding aid for the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives Collection of Video Materials, 1980-2005 LSC.2231
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Curation Series: Angela Brinskele, Series 4.
  - [9 Clips] (Box 3, Item 24)
    From the VHS tape's case. 1 - "An amusing animated short celebrating black culture by focusing on black hairstyles. Produced by Ayoka Chenzira." 2 - Illusions. "The story of creative black women who are pitted against a Hollywood studio during WWII also examines the reasons behind the absence of black figures in American cinematic history. Written, directed, and produced by Julie Dash." 3 - Red Rwa. "Inspired and made in memory of Kalbinder Kaur Hayre, a young Asian woman who was killed by three racist youth, this program explored the shared experiences of oppression among ethnic groups in Britain. Produced by Prathibha Parmer." 4 - "Lesbians nominated at 1989 Grammy Awards: Tracy Chapman, Melissa Etheridge." 5 - "USA Today: Lesbian Parents; Legal Problems" from 3/6/1989. 6 - To a Safer Place. "The Story of Shirley Turcotte, a woman who was sexually abused as a child and her brave efforts to make peace with her past." 7 - Indians, Outlaws, and Angie Debo. "Angie Debo, at 95, recounts her move to Oklahoma in a covered wagon, and how she became a champion for Indian rights." 8 - CNN Currents. "Suicide Survivors." 9 - "Sonya, Live in Los Angeles; Roe VS Wade, Smeal VS Schafly."
  - [Velvet Underground February 1993] (Box 3, Item 25)
    Overview of Velvet Underground (record label) concert. Includes footage of craft sale beforehand, including handmade jewelry, t-shirts, paintings, musical instruments, etc. and informal interviews with the creators and concert attendees. Also features setup footage/sound check before the concert. Sound cuts out intermittently in the beginning of the tape.
  - [Dykes on Mikes May 1993; Comedy Central; k.d. lang] (Box 3, Item 26)
    Comedic and musical performances at Dykes on Mikes, including Alix Dobkin, Kelly Conway, Becky Black, and Liz Montgomery. MC June Doyle discusses various support groups for women intermittently, including support for women with serious medical issues. / Comedy Central Radio Active Television interview with Sandra Bernhard, then her performance on "The A List" followed by Larry Amrose. An episode of "Out There Comedy," the first lesbian and gay comedy show with comics Susanne Westenhoffer, Phranc, Bob Smith, Mark Davis, and Marga Gomez. / Performance special and commentary by musician k.d. lang.
  - [Alix Dobkin], 1987 (Box 3, Item 27)
    Musical performance by singer-songwriter Alix Dobkin from the Gay Cable Network. Presented by producer/TV personality Cheryl Nasser.
  - [Diane Germain Interview], 1993 (Box 3, Item 28)
    Brief interview from the "Our World" television program of Diane F. Germain, a psychiatric social worker and cartoonist. Presented by Jon Hoffman; interviewer Linda Gibbins.
  - [Take the Power; Miscellaneous Gay Cable TV] (Box 3, Item 29)
  - [Workshops; Lynn Lavner] (Box 3, Item 30)
  - Woman was created to serve man. Lesbian feminist views. Source: Marilyn Murphy., undated (Box 3, Item 31)
    Featuring Murphy, Germain, and Wolfe.
  - Sonia Johnson, 23-27 January 1993 (Box 3, Item 32)
    An informal talk (partially recorded). Original sleeve had the additional note (an alternate date): "Sonia Johnson 1/23/93 speaking at a private home. (First and last minutes missing). Bad Tape."
  - Jean Conger Roast, 4 November 1989 (Box 3, Item 33)
  - Donna Smith - 5 Beta Compilation, undated (Box 3, Item 34)
  - Bar Dykes - 1st Meeting, 7 March 1991 (Box 3, Item 35)
    History of L.A. Attached note reads "Amazing oral history of L.A. Dykes Bars, Sat March 7, 1991. Candid interviews with lesbians at the Mazer Archives by Degonia and other woman. Bars from 50's on in Los Angeles. Including bartender Barbara Kalish, who is living in Long Beach as of 2008 - interviewed by Marie Cartier. Bars Mentioned: Misfits, Culver City, 1974-75, Bobbie, Virginia, Marsha, Barbara, Anna, Helen. Star Room - Jo Heston (owner). Sister Suds, My Way > Washington Blvd. Gardena - had the real butch femme bars "The Club." Baseball teams mentioned too. Variety Pool & Tennis courts right on beach in Santa Monica. Canyon Club in Malibu. 1st Older LA Area Bars remembered."
  - Mazer Lesbian Archives for ALMS (Compilation tape). (Box 3, Item 36)
    1. Yolanda Retter on Oprah 2. SCWU Welcome to our Lesbian World 3. Pat Bond at OLOC.
  - Compilation: Cammermeyer, Gays in military, November 1992, January 1993 (Box 3, Item 37)
    Compilation: 11/12/92 Cammermeyer/Prime Time, 11/16/92 Cammermeyer/Larry King Live, 11/20/92 Gays in military/Nightline, 11/21/92 Saturday Night Live Skit - Gays in military, 11/24/92 CBS Evening News/Misc. Gays in military items, 1/6/93 Nightline on Colorado, Misc. Pieces, 1/26 Maria Shriver/First Person.
- OLOC (Old Lesbians Organizing for Change), Series 7.
  - First OLOC Type Meeting: West Coast Celebration, 24 April 1987 (Box 1, Item 17)
    Note on tape reads: "4/24/87 Poss. First OLOC Type Meeting? West Coast Celebration. On this tape: Lisa Ben (Edythe Ede), Mable Hampton, Meryl Markham, Mina Meyer, Jackie Bridgewater?, Jean Adelman - speaking, Barbara McDonald - speaking about ageism." Label on tape reads "Sat A.M. - West Coast Celeb, Saturday Adelman & Mac Donald."
  - Old Lesbian C & C II, San Francisco, CA., August 1989 (Box 1, Item 18)
    Pre & Post Dinner. Large label reads: West Coast Celebration and Conference of Old Lesbians II Dinner + Dancing San Francisco, CA August 1989.
  - Old Lesbian C & C II, San Francisco, CA., August 1989 (Box 1, Item 19)
    Entertainment Part 1, Dinner. Large label reads: West Coast Celebration and Conference of Old Lesbians II Entertainment Part 1. San Francisco, CA August 1989.
  - Old Lesbian C & C II, San Francisco, CA., August 1989 (Box 1, Item 20)
    Entertainment Part II, Dinner, Mother Tongue. Large label reads: West Coast Celebration and Conference of Old Lesbians II Entertainment Part II. San Francisco, CA August 1990 (sic)
  - OLOC Conference II San Francisco., 4 August 1989 (Box 1, Item 21)
    Scope and Content
    Conference begins.
  - OLOC Conference II San Francisco., 5 August 1989 (Box 1, Item 22)
    Conference continues in AM-PM (Poetry - Art - Pat Bond) Mother tongue.
  - OLOC Conference II San Francisco., 5 August 1989 (Box 1, Item 23)
    Eve. Mother Tongue - Cantina.
  - OLOC Fund Raiser, 10 March 1991 (Box 1, Item 24)
    Sunday L.A. at June Mazer Collection. Barbara Nolish and DeGrania Golove Hosted.
  - OLOC Panel #1: Our Community, Who Are We?, 16 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 25)
  - OLOC Panel #2: Confronting Our Challenges, 16 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 26)
  - OLOC Panel #2: Confronting Our Challenges, 16 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 27)
  - OLOC Panel #3: The World We Live In, 17 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 28)
  - OLOC Panel #4: Living Our Lives, 17 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 29)
  - OLOC Panel #4: Living Our Lives, 17 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 30)
  - OLOC Fishbowl, 18 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 31)
  - OLOC Fishbowl, 18 August 1996 (Box 1, Item 32)
  - OLOC Summer Gathering 2002, 17 August 2002 (Box 1, Item 33)
    Panel #4: Ageism. 8/17/2002. Labeled "Tape 4/5."
  - OLOC Summer Gathering 2002, 18 August 2002 (Box 1, Item 34)
    Panel #5: How Politics Affect Our Community and Personal Lives. 8/18/2002. Labeled "Tape 5/5."
  - Old Lesbians Conference: Closing ceremony, April 1987 (Box 1, Item 35)
  - Old Lesbians- Friday Night, 24 April 1987 (Box 1, Item 36)
- SCWU (Southern California Women for Understanding), Series 8.
  - Welcome to Our Lesbian World - SCWU - 1983. Wendy's Tape, 10 June 1983 (Box 1, Item 12)
  - SCWU - Welcome to Our Lesbian World: A Lesbian Odyssey 1985 #6 (Box 1, Item 13)
    Label on tape reads "Property of June L. Mazer Lesbian Collection." Attached note reads "Fantastic Show Produced by Bunny Mac. Cast is key people in SCWU. Use entire tape for ALMS. 1986.
  - Camp SCWU 1990: Herstory: Ivy Bottini, Donna Smith, and Robin Tyler (Box 1, Item 14)
    Note attached reads "Donna Smith, Born 1919. Talks about going to gay bars in L.A. in 1940. (Great Bar stories early). Robin Tyler. Ivy Bottini."
  - SCWU 15th Birthday Party, 10 August 1991 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - SCWU 15th Annual Meeting, 19 October 1991 (Box 1, Item 16)